Theoretical and conceptual frameworks guide the paths of a research and offer the foundation for establish‎ing its credibility. Though these terms seem similar, they are different from each other in concept and in their roles in the research inquiry. However, many students ﬁnd it difﬁcult and confusing to distinguish between these two closely related frameworks while deﬁning their roles in their research.